http://www.williamsburgva.gov/government/privacy-policy-photo-acknowledgements

Show/Hide
UPDATED Nov. 24, 2020:
WJCC Schools Return to Learn: Forward - For the latest school information, visit wjccschools.org/forward.
FORWARD WILLIAMSBURG REOPENING PLAN -  Phase 3 - City of Williamsburg Public buildings will be open.   All services remain available online or by alternative means.  Citizens will need to check in and mask and temperature screening are required.  Staff will be on alternating shifts, others will be teleworking.  Quarterpath Recreation Center remains closed.
Williamsburg Parks and Recreation will begin to reopen certain City park amenities following COVID-19 safety guidelines.
William & Mary Path Forward: Fall 2020
Colonial Williamsburg's Response to COVID-19
FORWARD VIRGINIA GUIDELINES
*City of Williamsburg Emergency Temporary Zoning Guidance for Phase 3 of Forward Virginia
Business assistance information can be found at https://www.YesWilliamsburg.com.
The City's telephone hotline (for city service questions):  (757) 259-7200 and the Virginia Health Dept. call center (for COVID-19 questions/concerns):  (757) 594-7069.
HomeServicesAnimal ControlCedar Grove Cemetery Community BuildingDirections and HoursDog Park CommunicationseNotification Sign UpFacilities Rental and InformationQuarterpath Room RentalWaller Mill Park Shelter RentalCommunity BuildingGarbage and RecyclingHuman Services ProgramsLibraryMosquito ControlNew Resident ChecklistOnline Surplus AuctionParkingParks and RecreationPay Bills OnlinePay Parking Tickets OnlinePermits & LicensesProperty InformationPublic SafetyReport Public Works IssuesTax InformationUtilitiesVoter RegistrationWilliamsburg WifiWiFi Zone-Coverage AreaDowntown Area Map (PDF)WMSBG TV48 InformationOn DemandYouth Sports Online RegistrationGovernmentAbout WilliamsburgBoards and CommissionsLocal Elected/Appointed OfficialsVision & MissionGreen WilliamsburgPublic MeetingsDirectionsOrganizational Chart (PDF)Virginia Employment Commission City ProfileCity Limits Street Listing (PDF)HistoryMobile Apps and AlertsTax InformationCommunicationseNotification Sign UpCITIBOTCity CalendarsFacility RentalsFrequently Asked Questions.Job OpeningsLibraryNewsHighlightsOnline FormsBusiness Roundtables - Email Notification RequestComments Regarding Cox CommunicationsPermission to FilmPublic Works PortalRequest for a Greeting LetterRequest for a Letter of Recognition/CommendationRequest for Issuance of ProclamationWaller Mill Facilities Request FormWater Disconnection RequestWater/Sewer Online Applications for Businesses and Residential OwnersWMSBG TV48 Bulletin Board AnnouncementSpecial Events PermitProperty Information SystemSpecial Events PermitNewsroomPrivacy Policy & Photo AcknowledgementsDepartments A-HCity CouncilCity Manager's OfficeCodes Compliance Commissioner of the RevenueEconomic DevelopmentEmergency Preparedness Finance FireGreen WilliamsburgHuman ResourcesHuman ServicesDepartment I-ZInformation TechnologyParks & RecreationPlanningPolicePublic Works and UtilitiesPurchasing Real Estate AssessmentTreasurerVoter RegistrarWilliamsburg Redevelopment and Housing AuthorityTransparency in City GovernmentBids/ProposalsBiennial Goals & Initiatives City BudgetCity CodeComprehensive Annual Financial Reports (CAFR)2013 Comprehensive Plan Council Policies and Procedures (PDF)Economic Development Strategic PlanFreedom of InformationLegislative PrioritiesNewsroomNational Citizen Survey ResultsPerformance Management DashboardsOpen Forum OnlinePublic MeetingsPublic NoticesSubdivision OrdinanceWater Quality ReportChannel 48
Basic InformationZoning OrdinanceStaff DirectoryResidentsPay Bills OnlineAnimal ControlAttractions and MapsBoards and CommissionsBudgetCedar Grove Cemetery City CodeCity CalendarsCommunityDowntown Parking PlaneNotification Sign UpFacilitiesCommunity Building Municipal BuildingParking in WilliamsburgTransportation CenterWaller Mill ParkLibraryFirePoliceQuarterpath Recreation CenterWilliamsburg-James City County CourthouseFrequently Asked QuestionsGarbage & RecyclingHuman Services ProgramsNational Citizen Survey ResultsNeighborhood InformationNeighborhood GuideNeighborhood Relations CommitteeNeighborhood GuideResident Information GuideNew Resident InformationOnline Surplus AuctionPublic MeetingsPublic SafetyPublic Works RequestsPermits & LicensesStudent InformationWilliam & MaryStudent NewsGreen City InitiativesWilliamsburg-James City County SchoolsStaff DirectoryTax InformationTransparency in GovernmentOnline Youth Sports RegistrationUtilitiesVoter RegistrationVisitorsPLAY IN WILLIAMSBURGBoat RentalWaller Mill ParkDisc Golf CourseWaller Mill Dog ParkParks & FacilitiesQuarterpath Recreation CenterWalking TrailsVISIT IN WILLIAMSBURGWilliamsburg Lodging & AttractionsColonial WilliamsburgBusch Gardens WilliamsburgWilliam & MaryJamestown Settlement & American Revolution Museum at YorktownEXPLORE WILLIAMSBURG4th of July CelebrationsBrief HistoryThe Arts in WilliamsburgFacilitiesDowntown Area Map (PDF)Historic Triangle MapParkingParks & RecreationLibrary Williamsburg Area TransportWilliamsburg Farmers MarketBusinessDOING BUSINESSFood TrucksAbout WilliamsburgAvailable Commercial PropertiesBids/ProposalsBusiness LicenseBusiness Licenses & TaxesPermit ProcessPay Bills OnlinePermits OnlineProperty Information SystemSurplus PropertyTax RatesTourism Contingency FundTourism Development FundRESOURCESEconomic Development WebsiteEconomic Development AuthorityArchitectural Review BoardTourism Promotion Contingency FundingBoard of Zoning AppealsCodes Compliance DivisionDowntown Parking PlanFrequently Asked QuestionsNational Citizen Survey ResultsPlanning CommissionPlanning DepartmentCity Shop and Dine MapI Want To...APPLY/REGISTER FORBoards and CommissionsBusiness LicenseCigarette Tax StampsConstruction PermitsDog LicenseEmail and Emergency AlertsEmploymentOnline Construction PermitsParking PermitsRecreation Classes/SportsRoom & Meal TaxSpecial Event PermitsTour Guide LicenseTourism Promotion Contingency FundingVehicle RegistrationWater/Sewer ConnectionOnline Youth Sports RegistrationTourism Development FundPAY ONLINEPersonal Property TaxReal Estate TaxWater Utility BillParking TicketsRESERVECommunity Building Quarterpath Recreation CenterWaller Mill Park SheltersREQUESTCouncil ProclamationCouncil Greeting LetterCouncil Recognition/CommendationREPORTAnimal ControlCodes ViolationsRecycling IssuesStorm Drainage ProblemsStreets IssuesWaste Disposal IssuesWater/Sewer IssuesPublic Works RequestsVIEWARB GuidelinesAvailable PropertiesBids and ProposalsBiennial Goals Initiatives and OutcomesCity BudgetCity CalendarsCity Code2013 Comprehensive Plan Construction PermitsCouncil Meetings On DemandFAQsFacilitesNewsroomPerformance DashboardsPlanning Commission Meetings On DemandProperty Information SystemPublic NoticesSubdivision OrdinanceSite MapZoning OrdinanceLEARN MORE ABOUTCedar Grove CemeteryCollege of William & MaryColonial WilliamsburgEconomic DevelopmentElectionsEmergency Preparedness Human Services ProgramsLegislative PrioritiesPublic SafetyGarbage and RecyclingUtilitiesWaller Mill ParkBrief HistoryTransparency in City GovernmentWilliamsburg-James City County Schools
Jump to subpage...
About Williamsburg+Boards and CommissionsLocal Elected/Appointed OfficialsVision & MissionGreen WilliamsburgPublic MeetingsDirectionsOrganizational Chart (PDF)Virginia Employment Commission City ProfileCity Limits Street Listing (PDF)HistoryMobile Apps and AlertsTax InformationCommunications+eNotification Sign UpCITIBOTCity CalendarsFacility RentalsFrequently Asked Questions.Job OpeningsLibraryNewsHighlightsOnline Forms+Business Roundtables - Email Notification RequestComments Regarding Cox CommunicationsPermission to FilmPublic Works PortalRequest for a Greeting LetterRequest for a Letter of Recognition/CommendationRequest for Issuance of ProclamationWaller Mill Facilities Request FormWater Disconnection RequestWater/Sewer Online Applications for Businesses and Residential OwnersWMSBG TV48 Bulletin Board AnnouncementSpecial Events PermitProperty Information SystemSpecial Events PermitNewsroomPrivacy Policy & Photo AcknowledgementsDepartments A-H+City CouncilCity Manager's OfficeCodes Compliance Commissioner of the RevenueEconomic DevelopmentEmergency Preparedness Finance FireGreen WilliamsburgHuman ResourcesHuman ServicesDepartment I-Z+Information TechnologyParks & RecreationPlanningPolicePublic Works and UtilitiesPurchasing Real Estate AssessmentTreasurerVoter RegistrarWilliamsburg Redevelopment and Housing AuthorityTransparency in City Government+Bids/ProposalsBiennial Goals & Initiatives City BudgetCity CodeComprehensive Annual Financial Reports (CAFR)2013 Comprehensive Plan Council Policies and Procedures (PDF)Economic Development Strategic PlanFreedom of InformationLegislative PrioritiesNewsroomNational Citizen Survey ResultsPerformance Management DashboardsOpen Forum OnlinePublic MeetingsPublic NoticesSubdivision OrdinanceWater Quality ReportChannel 48
Basic InformationZoning OrdinanceStaff Directory
The City of Williamsburg follows the state guidelines for on-line privacy that read...
"It is the policy of the Commonwealth of Virginia that personal information about citizens will be collected only to the extent necessary to provide the service or benefit desired; that only appropriate information will be collected; that the citizen shall understand the reason the information is being collected and be able to examine their personal record which is maintained by a public body."
The City of Williamsburg's website:
Does not require you to provide any personal information to download files or reports or view information.
Contains links to other websites. The City of Williamsburg is not responsible for the privacy or the content of these websites.
Asks you to provide enough personal information in order to provide you with services or information that you request.
May be unable to provide your requested service or information if you choose not to provide us with the information needed.
Does not provide personal information to any other person, entity or organization without your consent, unless required by law.
Does not place a "cookie" on your computer. A "cookie" stores information on the user's computer that allows the browser to remember some specific information when visiting that site.
Does not track your movements through the website.
Does automatically log technical information for anonymous statistics reports to increase performance and maintain security of this site.
If you have any questions, please contact info@williamsburgva.gov.
The personal information collected by the City of Williamsburg, including forums, surveys, discussions, will be used to inform the Jurisdiction’s decision making process on new initiatives, programs, service, spending allocations etc. The Jurisdiction only collects your email address and personal information necessary for specific initiatives posted on the City of Williamsburg. Sections 26(c) and (e) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act are the legislated authorities for the collection of personal information. Unless requested, please do not include personal information that identifies you or other individuals when submitting content to the City of Williamsburg. Personal information that is not requested will be deleted and not considered in the evaluation of new initiatives etc.
Photography/Images
All images and text on the City of Williamsburg website are copyrighted  and are protected by applicable laws. Republication or redistribution of this content, including by framing or by similar means, is expressly prohibited without the prior written consent.
Colonial Williamsburg Pictures: Photos courtesy of The Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, Williamsburg, VA.
The William & Mary pictures: Photos courtesy of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA.
View Full Site
